Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Wilson, Harris R. C. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, Helen Wortham James (Box 96)
  - Wilson, J. Gordon (Box 96)
  - Wilson, J. W. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, James (Box 96)
  - Wilson, John M. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, Oren F. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, S. H. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, T. Gordon (Box 96)
  - Wilson, W. P. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 96)
  - Wimmel, Robert Campbell (Box 96)
  - Wimmer, Aug. (Box 96)
  - Windle, Mary Frances (Box 96)
  - Windt, Georg von (Box 96)
  - Wing, Andrew S. (Box 96)
  - Winge, O. (Box 96)
  - Winkelhagen, Juan (Box 96)
  - Winkler, Dr. (Box 96)
  - Winkler, John K. (Box 96)
  - Winkler, W. (Box 96)
  - Winn, Mrs. C. M. (Box 96)
  - Winship, Mrs. Charles H. (Box 96)
  - Winslow, Charles Edward Amory (Box 96)
  - Winsor, Henry (Box 96)
  - Winsor, Max (Box 96)
  - Winston, A. P. (Box 96)
  - Winton, W. M. (Box 96)
  - Witmer, Leightner (Box 96)
  - Witschi, Emil (Box 96)
  - Wolman, Leo (Box 96)
  - Wood, Ben D. (Box 96)
  - Wood, Casey A. (Box 96)
  - Wood, Francis Carter (Box 96)
  - Wood, George C. (Box 96)
  - Wood, Thomas D. (Box 96)
  - Wood, Mrs. Willis D. (Box 96)
  - Woodbridge, Frederick J. E. (Box 96)
  - Woodbury, George (Box 96)
  - Woodhull, John F. (Box 96)
  - Woodruff, Charles E. (Box 96)
  - Woodruff, Lorande Loss (Box 96)
  - Woods, Arthur (Box 96)
  - Woods, Charles D. (Box 96)
  - Woods, Frederick A., 1903-1939; 65 items (Box 96)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- First Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Woodward, K. W. (Box 96)
  - Woodward, Laura E. (Box 96)
  - Woodward, Robert B. (Box 96)
  - Woodward, Robert S. (Box 96)
  - Woodward, Verney D. (Box 96)
  - Woodworth, C. M. (Box 97)
  - Woodworth, C. W. (Box 97)
  - Woodworth, R. J. (Box 97)
  - Woodworth, William McMichael (Box 97)
  - Work, Monroe N. (Box 97)
  - Wright, Albert A. (Box 97)
  - Wright, H. R. T. (Box 97)
  - Wright, Henry C. (Box 97)
  - Wright, John Dutton (Box 97)
  - Wright, Philip G. (Box 97)
  - Wright, Quincy (Box 97)
  - Wright, Richard T. (Box 97)
  - Wright, Sewall (Box 97)
  - Wullen, Hilda H. (Box 97)
  - Wurzinger, Stephen (Box 97)
  - Wymore, Mary Isabel (Box 97)
  - Yale University (Box 97)
  - Yale University Press (Box 97)
  - Yanagiswa, Y. (Box 97)
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1899-1933; 7 folders (155 items) (Box 97)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters; Eugenics; Eugenics Record Office; Graduate study; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Psychology; Publication; Recommendations; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1899-1909 (Box 97)
    - Folder 2, 1911 (Box 97)
    - Folder 3, 1912 (Box 97)
    - Folder 4, 1913-1916 (Box 97)
    - Folder 5, 1917-1921 (Box 97)
    - Folder 6, 1922-1924 (Box 97)
    - Folder 7, 1925-1933 (Box 97)
  - Young, Allyn A. (Box 97)
  - Zeleny, Charles (Box 97)
  - Zinn, Earl F. (Box 97)
  - Zoological Society of London (Box 97)
- Series II. Cold Spring Harbor Series, 1899-1946; 20 linear feet (Box 98-136)
  Correspondence, reports, accounts, and other records relating to operation of the various laboratories at Cold Spring Harbor. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically
  - Subseries A. Administrative Correspondence, 1899-1939 (Box 98-106)
    Correspondence and documentation of Davenport's. Subseries A contains Davenport's correspondence with administrators of the Carnegie Institution of Washington regarding the operation of Cold Spring Harbor. The bulk is comprised of mundane correspondence, financial accounts, and reports. Correspondence with John Wirt, William Gilbert, and William Barnum deals with salaries and other financial matters and publications, and there is considerable correspondence with the presidents of the Carnegie Institution of Washington, Robert Woodward and John Merriam. Perhaps the most generally useful material relates to Davenport's early efforts in creating the station at Cold Spring Harbor.]
    - Barnum, William, 3 folders (Box 98)
      - Folder 1, 1904-1905 (Box 98)
      - Folder 2, 1906 (Box 98)
      - Folder 3, 1907-1908 (Box 98)
    - Blakeslee, Albert (Box 98)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 98-100)
      - C.I.W., 1909; 4 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1910-1911; 3 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1912-1913; 3 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1914-1915; 3 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1916; 3 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1917; 2 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1918 (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1919; 3 folders (Box 98)
      - C.I.W., 1920; 4 folders (Box 99)
      - C.I.W., 1921; 6 folders (Box 99)
      - C.I.W., 1922; 5 folders (Box 99)
      - C.I.W., 1923; 6 folders (Box 99)
      - C.I.W., 1924; 5 folders (Box 99)
      - C.I.W., 1925; 7 folders (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Articles of Incorporation (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Board of Trustees, 1920-1921 (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Committee on Exhibits (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Division of Publications, 1926; 2 folders (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Division of Publications, 1927; 2 folders (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Division of Publications, 1928; 3 folders (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. Executive Committee - Acts and Resolutions, 3 folders (Box 100)
      - C.I.W. - Pension System (Box 100)
    - Cold Spring Harbor (Box 100)
      - Cold Spring Harbor - T. Jones property deeded to C.I.W., 1926 (Box 100)
      - Cold Spring Harbor Records of Staff Meetings, 1915-1934 (Box 100)
    - Davenport, Charles B. (Box 100)
      - A Summary of Progress in Experimental Evolution (Box 100)
      - Invitations (Box 100)
      - To Executive Committee of Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1904 (Box 100)
      - To Trustees of Carnegie Institution of Washington, 1903 Mar. 5 (Box 100)
    - Dept. of Genetics - History (Box 100)
    - Eugenics Record Office - Expenses for 1919 (Box 100)
    - Eugenics Record Office - History (Box 100)
    - Gilbert, Walter M., 1905-1926; 10 folders (321 items) (Box 100-101)
      Biographical and personal data -- Belling, John; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
      - 1905 (Box 100)
      - 1906 (Box 100)
      - 1907 (Box 100)
      - 1908 (Box 100)
      - 1926, 6 folders (Box 101)
    - Mayor, Alfred G. (Box 101)
    - Merriam, John C., 1918-1940; 66 folders (1,786 items) (Box 101-103)
      Academic freedom; Anthropology; Behavioral genetics, IQ; Cancer, chemotherapy; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Educational matters; Eugenics; Eugenics Record Office; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics; Genetics of plants; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Laughlin, Harry Hamilton; Mouse genetics; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Political issues; Publication; Rabbit genetics; Radiation genetics; Rat genetics; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Scientific refugees
      - 1918-1920 (Box 101)
      - 1921, 4 folders (Box 101)
      - 1922, 6 folders (Box 101)
      - 1923, 5 folders (Box 101)
      - 1924, 4 folders (Box 101)
      - 1925, 5 folders (Box 101-102)
      - 1926, 5 folders (Box 102)
      - 1927, 5 folders (Box 102)
      - 1928, 6 folders (Box 102)
      - 1929, 6 folders (Box 102)
      - 1930, 4 folders (Box 102-103)
      - 1931, 2 folders (Box 103)
      - 1932, 3 folders (Box 103)
      - 1933, 4 folders (Box 103)
      - 1934, 3 folders (Box 103)
      - 1935-1936 (Box 103)
      - 1937-1939 (Box 103)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1890 - 1899 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1900 – 1908 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1910 – 1911 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1912 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1913 - 1915 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1923 – 1924 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1930 – 1932 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: 1934 – 1942 (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: Obituaries – Colleagues (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: Obituaries – C. B. Davenport (Box 103)
      - Newspaper clippings: Date Unknown (Box 103)
    - Ray Society (Box 103)
    - Romanes, S. J. (Box 103)
    - Shull, George H. (Box 103)
    - Station For Experimental Evolution, 16 folders (Box 103)
      - 1st. Annual Report (Box 103)
      - Annual Reports - Davenport, Shull, Lutz, Johnson (Box 103)
        *Davenport, C.B. Johnson, R.H. Lutz, F.E. Shull, G.H.
      - Associates (Box 103)
      - Beginnings (Box 103)
      - Budget for 1905 (Box 103)
      - Building Estimates (Box 103)
      - Exchange of Publications, 1904-1930; 2 folders (Box 103)
        - Folder 1, 1904-1907 (Box 103)
        - Folder 2, 1908-1930 (Box 103)
      - Exhibit, November 21, 1925, 1925 November 21 (Box 103)
      - Financial Records (Box 103)
      - Floor Plans (Box 103)
      - Opening Ceremony, 1904 June 11 (Box 103)
      - Staff 1914 (Box 103)
        *Gilbert, Walter M
      - Staff 1922 (Box 103)
      - Staff 1924 (Box 103)
      - Supplies (Box 103)
    - Thiselton-Dyer, W. T. (Box 103)
    - Tortugas Laboratory (Box 103)
    - Walcott, Charles (Box 103)
    - Wirt, John L., 1905-1929; 31 folders (Box 103-104)
      Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
      - 1905-1906 (Box 103)
      - 1907 (Box 103)
      - 1908, 2 folders (Box 103)
      - 1910, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1911 (Box 104)
      - 1912 (Box 104)
      - 1913 (Box 104)
      - 1914 (Box 104)
      - 1915 (Box 104)
      - 1916 (Box 104)
      - 1917 (Box 104)
      - 1918 (Box 104)
      - 1919 (Box 104)
      - 1920, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1921-1922 (Box 104)
      - 1923 (Box 104)
      - 1924, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1925, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1926, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1927, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1928, 2 folders (Box 104)
      - 1929, 3 folders (Box 104)
    - Woodward, R. S., 1899-1923; 49 folders (1,228 items) (Box 105-106)
      Bibliographical matters; Burbank, Luther; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; Evolution; Jennings, Herbert Spencer; Metz, Charles W.; Publication; Rabbit genetics; Recommendations; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Shull, George Harrison; Solicitations for support or contribution; Tower, William L.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Whitman, Charles Otis; World War I -- Impact on science; Zoology
      - 1899-1904 (Box 105)
      - 1905, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1906, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1907, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1908, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1909, 4 folders (Box 105)
      - 1910, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1911 (Box 105)
      - 1912, 2 folders (Box 105)
      - 1913, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1914, 3 folders (Box 105)
      - 1915, 2 folders (Box 106)
      - 1916 (Box 106)
      - 1917, 3 folders (Box 106)
      - 1918, 2 folders (Box 106)
      - 1919, 6 folders (Box 106)
      - 1920, 5 folders (Box 106)
      - 1921-1923 (Box 106)
  - Subseries B. Records of Assistants, 1904-1946 (Box 107-136)
    Records kept by Davenport at Cold Spring Harbor relative to his full-time and part-time professional assistants, including the maintenance staff. Materials include some correspondence, reports, accounts, research plans, and bibliographies.
    Included in this subseries are records of the separate laboratories at Cold Spring Harbor, including the Station for Experimental Evolution and the Eugenics Record Office, as well as administrative records of the Department of Genetics.
    Finally, there are some materials that do not relate directly to the Cold Spring Harbor laboratories, including some relating to professional organizations with which Davenport was affiliated, such as the Eugenics Research Association, the Eugenics Society of America, the Nassau County Association, and the National Committee for Mental Hygiene.
    - Table of Contents (Box 107)
    - Akin, Frank J. (Box 107)
    - Allen, Blanche (Box 107)
    - Allen, Ezra (Box 107)
    - Allen, Frank (Box 107)
    - Allen, W. R. (Box 107)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 107)
    - American Eugenics Society, 3 folders (Box 107)
      - Committee on Research, 5 folders (Box 107)
        - Correspondence B - E (Box 107)
        - Correspondence F - J (Box 107)
        - Correspondence K - S (Box 107)
        - Correspondence T - W (Box 107)
        - Folder 5 (Box 107)
      - Popular Education Committee (Box 107)
      - Wallace, Anna M., 3 folders (Box 107)
        - Folder 1, 1925-1926 (Box 107)
        - Folder 2, 1927 (Box 107)
        - Folder 3, 1928-1929 (Box 107)
    - American Social Hygiene Association - Snow, William F. (Box 107)
    - Anderson, E. G. (Box 107)
    - Anderson, Karl E. (Box 107)
    - Anderson, Pearl (Box 107)
    - Andrus, Margaret, 1920-1925; 4 folders (109 items) (Box 107)
      American Eugenics Society; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Eugenics; Publication
      - Folder 1, 1920-1922 (Box 107)
      - Folder 2, 1923 (Box 107)
      - Folder 3, 1924 (Box 107)
      - Folder 4, 1925 (Box 107)
    - Avery, Amos G. (Box 107)
    - Avery, Billings T. (Box 107)
    - Babcock, Margaret R. (Box 107)
    - Banker, Howard J., 1914-1950; 5 folders (125 items) (Box 107)
      Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Human genetics; Publication
      - Folder 1, 1914-1916 (Box 107)
      - Folder 2, 1918-1922 (Box 107)
      - Folder 3, 1923-1926 (Box 107)
      - Folder 4, 1927-1930 (Box 107)
      - Folder 5, 1931-1950 (Box 107)
    - Banta, Arthur M., 1903-1946; 19 folders (370 items) (Box 107-108)
      Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Business; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Evolution; Fellowships, assistantships; International Congress of Genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology
      - Folder 1, 1903-1911 (Box 107)
      - Folder 2, 1913-1916 (Box 107)
      - Folder 3, 1917-1919 (Box 107)
      - Folder 4, 1921-1923 (Box 108)
      - Folder 5, 1924 (Box 108)
      - Folder 6, 1925 (Box 108)
      - Folder 7, 1926 (Box 108)
      - Folder 8, 1927 (Box 108)
      - Folder 9, 1928 (Box 108)
      - Folder 10, 1929 (Box 108)
      - Folder 11, 1930 (Box 108)
      - Folder 12, 1930 (Box 108)
      - Folder 13, 1931 (Box 108)
      - Folder 14, 1932 (Box 108)
      - Folder 15, 1933 (Box 108)
      - Folder 16, 1934-1935 (Box 108)
      - Folder 17, 1936-1937 (Box 108)
      - Folder 18, 1938-1939 (Box 108)
      - Folder 19, 1940-1946 (Box 108)
    - Banta, Edith (Box 108)
    - Barrows, Florence L., 1927-1931; 3 folders (60 items) (Box 108)
      Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
      - Folder 1, 1927 (Box 108)
      - Folder 2, 1928 (Box 108)
      - Folder 3, 1929-1931 (Box 108)
    - Bartlett, Emily M. (Box 108)
    - Basset, Gardner C. (Box 108)
    - Bates, Robert W. (Box 108)
    - Baume, Frances Elinor (Box 108)
    - Beers, Clifford W., 1916-1932; 7 folders (Box 108)
      National Committee for Mental Hygiene
      - Folder 1, 1916-1918 (Box 108)
      - Folder 2, 1919-1921 (Box 108)
      - Folder 3, 1923-1924 (Box 108)
      - Folder 4, 1925 (Box 108)
      - Folder 5, 1926-1927 (Box 108)
      - Folder 6, 1928 (Box 108)
      - Folder 7, 1929-1932 (Box 108)
    - Behre, Ellinor H. (Box 109)
    - Bell, Dora (Box 109)
    - Bell, Mary (Box 109)
    - Belling, John, 1916-1940; 7 folders (40 items) (Box 109)
      Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Cytogenetics; Publication
      - Folder 1, 1916-1925 (Box 109)
      - Folder 2, 1926-1927 (Box 109)
      - Folder 3, 1928 (Box 109)
      - Folder 4, 1929 (Box 109)
      - Folder 5, 1930 (Box 109)
      - Folder 6, 1931-1932 (Box 109)
      - Folder 7, 1933-1940 (Box 109)
    - Belzer, Katharine (Box 109)
    - Benney, Isabel (Box 109)
    - Bergner, Dorothy (Box 109)
    - Bermuda Biological Station, 1926-1932; 9 folders (Box 109)
      - Folder 1, 1926-1927 (Box 109)
      - Folder 2, 1928-1929 (Box 109)
      - Folders 3-5: 1930 a, b, c, 3 folders (Box 109)
      - Folders 6-7: 1931 a, b, 2 folders (Box 109)
      - Folders 8-9: 1932 a, b, 2 folders (Box 109)
      - Blueprints (Box 109)
    - Blakeslee, Albert Francis, 1900-1943; 22 folders (390 items) (Box 109-110)
      Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Burbank, Luther; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Genetics of plants -- Crepis; Genetics of plants -- Datura; Genetics of plants -- Mucor; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Research Council; Poultry genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
      - Folder 1, 1900-1912 (Box 109)
      - Folder 2, 1913-1914 (Box 109)
      - Folder 3, 1915 (Box 109)
      - Folder 4, 1916-1919 (Box 109)
      - Folder 5, 1920-1921 (Box 109)
      - Folder 6, 1922-1923 (Box 109)
      - Folder 7, 1924 (Box 109)
      - Folder 8, 1925 (Box 109)
      - Folder 9, 1926 (Box 109)
      - Folder 10, 1927 (Box 109)
      - Folder 11, 1928 (Box 109)
      - Folder 12, 1929, Jan. - May (Box 110)
      - Folder 13, 1929, June - Dec. (Box 110)
      - Folder 14, 1930 (Box 110)
      - Folder 15, 1930 (Box 110)
      - Folder 16, 1931 (Box 110)
      - Folder 17, 1932, Jan. - March (Box 110)
      - Folder 18, 1932, April - Sept. (Box 110)
      - Folder 19, 1933 (Box 110)
      - Folder 20, 1934a (Box 110)
      - Folder 21, 1934b (Box 110)
      - Folder 22, 1935-1943 (Box 110)
    - Bloomer, Itelen (Box 110)
    - Boulton, Laura Crayton (Box 110)
    - Boulton, Rudyerd (Box 110)
    - Breitenbecher, J. K. (Box 110)
    - Brown, Bernice (Box 110)
    - Brown, Leland A., 1919-1951; 2 folders (58 items) (Box 110)
      Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Graduate study -- Harvard University; Rafinesque, Constantine; Teaching; Zoology
      - Folder 1, 1919-1930 (Box 110)
      - Folder 2, 1931-1951 (Box 110)
    - Buchholz, John T. (Box 110)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington (C.I.W.) (Box 110)
      - Department of Plant Physiology (Box 110)
      - Executive Committee (Box 110)
      - Leases (Box 110)
      - Photographs (Box 110)
      - Wawepex Society Lease (Box 110)
    - Cartledge, J. Lincoln, 1919-1946; 5 folders (86 items) (Box 110)
      Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Genetics of plants -- Datura; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Research support
      - Folder 1, 1919-1926 (Box 110)
      - Folder 2, 1927-1934 (Box 110)
      - Folder 3, 1935 (Box 110)
      - Folder 4, 1936-1937 (Box 110)
      - Folder 5, 1938-1946 (Box 110)
    - Cartledge, Mrs. Maria Hilliard (Box 110)
    - Cauthen, George E. (Box 110)
    - Chambers, Margaret B. (Box 110)
    - Chantler, Mary (Box 110)
    - Chapman, L. C. (Box 110)
    - Charles, Donald R. (Box 110)
    - Chidester, Floyd E. (Box 110)
    - Child Health Demonstration Committee (Box 110)
      *Evans, Lester J.
    - Children's Aid Society, N.Y. (Box 110)
      *Falconer, Douglas P.
    - Childs, J. Calvin (Box 110)
    - Claflin, George H., 1912-1933; 14 folders (Box 110-111)
      - Folder 1, 1912-1913 (Box 110)
      - Folder 2, 1914-1920 (Box 110)
      - Folder 3, 1921 (Box 110)
      - Folder 4, 1922 (Box 110)
      - Folder 5, 1923 (Box 110)
      - Folder 6, 1924 (Box 111)
      - Folder 7, 1925 (Box 111)
      - Folder 8, 1926, Jan. - June (Box 111)
      - Folder 9, 1926, July - Dec. (Box 111)
      - Folder 10, 1927; 4 folders (Box 111)
      - Folder 11, 1928 (Box 111)
      - Folder 12, 1929 (Box 111)
      - Folder 13, 1930 (Box 111)
      - Folder 14, 1931-1933 (Box 111)
    - Clutter, O. R. (Box 111)
    - Cold Spring Harbor - Scientific Institutions (Box 111)
    - Cold Spring Harbor Village Park (Box 111)
    - Comunale, Marguerite (Box 111)
    - Conklin, Frances E. (Box 111)
    - Connell, Frank H. (Box 111)
    - Corbitt, Elsa A. (Box 111)
    - Couch, Mabel (Box 111)
    - Craig, James Anderson (Box 111)
    - Craighill, Caroline (Box 111)
    - Crane, Charles W. (Box 111)
    - Crockett, Nancy (Box 111)
    - Czechoslovak Eugenic Society in Prague (Box 111)
    - Darwin Anniversary Committee, 1907-1914; 8 folders (Box 111)
      American Association for the Advancement of Science; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; History of biology, especially genetics; Publication; Solicitations for support or contribution
      - Folder 1, 1907 (Box 111)
      - Folder 2, 1908, Jan. - July (Box 111)
      - Folder 3, 1908, Oct. - Dec. (Box 111)
      - Folder 4, 1909-1914 (Box 111)
      - Darwin Anniversary Committee. Donations, 4 folders (Box 111)
      - Poulton, E. B. "Fifty Years of Darwinism" (Box 111)
    - Davenport, Charles B., 2 folders (Box 111)
      - Application of Mendel's Law to Human Heredity (Box 111)
      - The New Views about Reversion (Box 111)
    - Dean, Bradford (Box 111)
    - Dean, Robert B. (Box 111)
    - Dean, Rollin C. (Box 111)
    - Dearborn, George N. (Box 112)
    - DeBalan, Mrs. B. (Box 112)
    - DeBaun, Lewis H. (Box 112)
    - Decamps, N. (Box 112)
    - Dechmann, Louis (Box 112)
    - Decker, M. B. (Box 112)
    - Dederer, Ebba A. (Box 112)
    - Dederer, Pauline H. (Box 112)
    - Deepdale Poultry Farm (Box 112)
    - DeForest, Henry W., 1907-1931; 3 folders (Box 112)
      Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory -- Property
      - Folder 1, 1907-1927 (Box 112)
      - Folder 2, 1928-1930 (Box 112)
      - Folder 3, 1931 (Box 112)
    - DeForest, Johnston (Box 112)
    - DeForest, Robert (Box 112)
    - Degener, L. M. (Box 112)
    - Delabarre, Frank A. (Box 112)
    - Delafield, Lewis L. (Box 112)
    - Delage, Yves (Box 112)
    - Delaney, John H. (Box 112)
    - Deleener, M. D. (Box 112)
    - Delipino, Victor (Box 112)
    - Delong, Dwight M. (Box 112)
    - Delt, Wilfred Mark (Box 112)
    - Demaree, Margaret (Box 112)
    - DeMilt, J. T. (Box 112)
    - Dengler, Paul L. (Box 112)
    - Dennett, Frances C. (Box 112)
    - Dennett, Mary Ware (Box 112)
      *Voluntary Parenthood League
    - Department of Experimental Evolution (Box 112)
    - Department of Genetics (Box 112-113)
      - Accounts, 1922-1927; 4 folders (Box 112)
      - Assistants 1926, 2 folders (Box 112)
      - Assistants 1927, 3 folders (Box 112)
      - Assistants 1928, 3 folders (Box 112)
      - Assistants 1929, 4 folders (Box 112)
      - Assistants 1930, 4 folders (Box 113)
      - Budget 1932 (Box 113)
      - Library (Box 113)
      - Organization (Box 113)
      - Organization and Budget, 1922; 3 folders (Box 113)
      - Twenty-fifth Anniversary Celebration, 1929; 2 folders (Box 113)